<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on My Personal Website</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on My Personal Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 14:52:54 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fabien.pean.pro/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Musculoskeletal Shoulder Simulation</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/projects/phd_shoulder/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/projects/phd_shoulder/</guid><description>&lt;p>Correct diagnosis and deep understanding of a condition is the general prerequisite for providing an optimal treatment. Injuries and diseases affecting the musculoskeletal system and their impact are difficult to reproduce in controlled and repeatable settings. Impairments greatly restrict the patient&amp;rsquo;s ability to carry out common daily tasks vital for remaining independent. In particular, many activities rely on the extensive reachability offered by the upper limb.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The shoulder offers the greatest range-of-motion in the whole human body and plays a key role in enabling the execution of common daily tasks vital for remaining independent, which is only possible thanks to its unique structure. Indeed, the shoulder consists of loosely connected bones maintained in their desired positions by many muscles, which play a vital role in moving the arm and transferring the load from the upper limb to the trunk. However, it means that the various observable properties are the result of a complex set of neurological processes, which coordinates the many muscles for actuating the upper limb. Active motion, as the result of conscious decision, is a key aspect of understanding pathology and their potential solution. Unfortunately, it is this particular aspect that is difficult to study for practical and ethical reasons. Alternative to clinical and ex-vivo studies falling under the aforementioned concerns, numerical models of the musculoskeletal system offer a great opportunity for an ethical, reproducible, and flexible means to analyze in-depth the human movement and its intrinsic properties. However, several outstanding challenges in modeling have long delayed the application of such models in concrete clinical and biomechanical scenarios.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>