<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My Personal Website</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/</link><description>Recent content on My Personal Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:27:05 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fabien.pean.pro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crafting a versatile generic function using concepts and unexpected pitfalls of implicit ranges like `std::filesystem::path`</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2024/12/crafting-a-versatile-generic-function-using-concepts-and-unexpected-pitfalls-of-implicit-ranges-like-stdfilesystempath/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2024/12/crafting-a-versatile-generic-function-using-concepts-and-unexpected-pitfalls-of-implicit-ranges-like-stdfilesystempath/</guid><description>Context During the course of my work, I was brought to develop a feature where the library user should be able upload a file or folder to a foreign storage. This post goes over my train of thought from a barebone function to a richer interface, covering some common use-cases. For the purpose of this post, upload will be reworded as print, where the argument is output to the console. A minor change, but relatively similar interface.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/home/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 15:03:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/home/about/</guid><description>Hello there ! Welcome to my personal website, I am currently senior simulation engineer at Virtonomy. Prior that, I defended my PhD at ETH Zurich where I was working on the musculoskeletal modeling and simulation of the shoulder, see here for more details.
In general, I am fond of numerical methods and modeling approaches in the field of computational science, especially solid mechanics, with an accent on high-performance computing. My passion revolves around the interactive simulation of deformable bodies.</description></item><item><title>Deep down the FOSS: an unexpected journey</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2023/04/deep-down-the-foss-an-unexpected-journey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2023/04/deep-down-the-foss-an-unexpected-journey/</guid><description>Once upon a VegaFEM It all began with a spark&amp;hellip;
On my spare time, I decided to sharpen my skills and change my mind by toying with VegaFEM, an open-source (BSD-3-Clause) middleware providing facilities for soft-body simulation in the realm of computer graphics. It has been developed by Jernej Barbič and his group over many years, yet, it does not have an official release on any major git repository hosting websites.</description></item><item><title>Starting a new job at Virtonomy</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2022/02/starting-a-new-job-at-virtonomy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2022/02/starting-a-new-job-at-virtonomy/</guid><description>On February 1st 2022, I officially start a new adventure as Senior Simulation Engineer at Virtonomy :tada: My mission there will be to develop methods and applications for the simulation of cardiovascular related medical scenarios :heart:, with the aim to shorten time to market for medical devices developers. Once this is well-established, direction orthopedics :rocket:</description></item><item><title>New paper published in Clinical Biomechanics</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2021/12/new-paper-published-in-clinical-biomechanics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2021/12/new-paper-published-in-clinical-biomechanics/</guid><description>My paper titled Computational analysis of subscapularis tears and pectoralis major transfers on muscular activity, published in Clinical Biomechanics, is now online ! It is freely accessible under a Creative Commons license, thanks to the agreement between ETH Zurich and Elsevier, at this url. This article brings a conclusion to a long journey as it is the last work elaborated during my PhD. Many thanks to my co-authors Dr. Philippe Favre and Prof.</description></item><item><title>Nitsche method for weakly enforced Dirichlet boundary conditions</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/boundarycondition_weak_nitsche/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/boundarycondition_weak_nitsche/</guid><description>Disclaimer For the sake of simplicity, the following post focuses on weak Dirichlet boundary conditions applied to the linear elastostatics problem. This document reflects my understanding and interpretation of the method. If you spot a mistake, please let me know !
Context Numerical models of physical systems are often represented as Boundary Value Problem, which consists of a Partial Differential Equation governing the domain accompanied by boundary conditions, known values on the boundary of the domain.</description></item><item><title>New paper published in Journal of Biomechanics</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2021/11/new-paper-published-in-journal-of-biomechanics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2021/11/new-paper-published-in-journal-of-biomechanics/</guid><description>My paper titled Influence of rotator cuff integrity on loading and kinematics before and after reverse shoulder arthroplasty published in Journal of Biomechanics is now online ! It is freely accessible under a Creative Commons license, thanks to the agreement between ETH Zurich and Elsevier, at this url</description></item><item><title>Dynamical system control</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/dynamical_system_control/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/dynamical_system_control/</guid><description>\(\newcommand{\T}{\mathsf{\small{T}}}\newcommand{\d}{\mathrm{d}}\)
Notations Let \(\mathbf{q},\mathbf{\dot q},\mathbf{\ddot q}\) be the generalized coordinates, velocities, and accelerations. The vector \(\mathbf{a}\) represent the controllable parameters, which are to be read as the activation parameters. The superscripts involving \(t\) will be used to denote time points such that \(\mathbf{q}^{t+\tau} = \mathbf{q}(t+\tau)\) represents the discrete value of \(\mathbf{q}\) at time \(t+\tau\), while subscript involving \(n\) as in \(\mathbf{q}_n^t\) will represent the value of \(\mathbf{q}^t\) at some iteration \(n\).</description></item><item><title>Musculoskeletal Shoulder Simulation</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/projects/phd_shoulder/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/projects/phd_shoulder/</guid><description>Correct diagnosis and deep understanding of a condition is the general prerequisite for providing an optimal treatment. Injuries and diseases affecting the musculoskeletal system and their impact are difficult to reproduce in controlled and repeatable settings. Impairments greatly restrict the patient&amp;rsquo;s ability to carry out common daily tasks vital for remaining independent. In particular, many activities rely on the extensive reachability offered by the upper limb.
The shoulder offers the greatest range-of-motion in the whole human body and plays a key role in enabling the execution of common daily tasks vital for remaining independent, which is only possible thanks to its unique structure.</description></item><item><title>PhD thesis defended with success</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2021/02/phd-thesis-defended-with-success/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2021/02/phd-thesis-defended-with-success/</guid><description>I am thrilled to announce that I successfully defended my PhD thesis. :tada::tada::tada:
Entitled &amp;ldquo;Computational Modeling and Simulation of the Shoulder for Functional Analysis of Orthopedic Surgery Outcomes&amp;rdquo;, it was carried out at ETH Zurich in collaboration with Balgrist University Hospital and Dr. Philippe Favre from Zimmer Biomet. During my PhD, I developed numerical models of the shoulder to better understand the musculoskeletal system during active movement under various clinical conditions and their treatments.</description></item><item><title>TR-BDF2</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/timestepping_tr-bdf2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/timestepping_tr-bdf2/</guid><description>Introduction TR-BDF2 is a composite time-stepping scheme operating on a single step with two substeps. The first substep is relying on the implicit midpoint method (trapezoidal rule), while the second substep uses the second order backward differentiation formula, hence the name TR-BDF2. It has been first described in [Bank1985], and is sometimes called the Bathe method after [Bathe2005]. The scheme is part of the Diagonally Implicit Runge Kutta (DIRK) family of methods.</description></item><item><title>Backward Differentiation Formula</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/timestepping_bdf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/timestepping_bdf/</guid><description>Backward Differentiation Formula Starting from an unknown continuous function of time \(\mathbf q(T)\), the solution can be found numerically at discretized time points \(T_n\) with \(n\in \mathbb N\) where, to simplify the notations \(\mathbf q_n = \mathbf q(T_n)\). The goal is to be able to compute \(\mathbf q_{n+1}\) from previous known discrete values. The BDF way to proceed is to assume that the real solution can be interpolated using Lagrange polynomials.</description></item><item><title>Theta method</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/timestepping_theta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/timestepping_theta/</guid><description>Notations Let be \(\mathbf{q}\) be a field function of time \(t\) and \(\mathbf{\dot q}, \mathbf{\ddot q}\) be its first and second derivatives with respect to time, \[ \begin{aligned} \mathbf{q} &amp;amp;= \mathbf{q}(t)\\ \mathbf{\dot q} &amp;amp;= \frac{\mathrm{d} \mathbf{q}}{\mathrm{d} t}\\ \mathbf{\ddot q} &amp;amp;= \frac{\mathrm{d} \mathbf{\dot q}}{\mathrm{d} t}\\ \end{aligned} \] In order to make the description of the time integration algorithms less abstract, one can think of $,, $ as position, velocity and acceleration. Moreover, the balance of momentum equation is considered for a concrete derivation of the scheme.</description></item><item><title>Implicit Euler</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/timestepping_implicit_euler/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/timestepping_implicit_euler/</guid><description>Notations Let be \(\mathbf{q}\) be a field function of time \(t\) and \(\mathbf{\dot q}, \mathbf{\ddot q}\) be its first and second derivatives with respect to time, \[ \begin{aligned} \mathbf{q} &amp;amp;= \mathbf{q}(t)\\ \mathbf{\dot q} &amp;amp;= \frac{\mathrm{d} \mathbf{q}}{\mathrm{d} t}\\ \mathbf{\ddot q} &amp;amp;= \frac{\mathrm{d} \mathbf{\dot q}}{\mathrm{d} t}\\ \end{aligned} \] In order to make the description of the time integration algorithms less abstract, one can think of $,, $ as position, velocity and acceleration. Moreover, the balance of momentum equation is considered for a concrete derivation of the scheme.</description></item><item><title>Implicit midpoint method</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/timestepping_implicit_midpoint_method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/timestepping_implicit_midpoint_method/</guid><description>Notations Let be \(\mathbf{q}\) be a field function of time \(t\) and \(\mathbf{\dot q}, \mathbf{\ddot q}\) be its first and second derivatives with respect to time \[ \left\{\begin{aligned} \mathbf{q} &amp;amp;= \mathbf{q}(t)\\ \mathbf{\dot q} &amp;amp;= \frac{\mathrm{d} \mathbf{q}}{\mathrm{d} t}\\ \mathbf{\ddot q} &amp;amp;= \frac{\mathrm{d} \mathbf{\dot q}}{\mathrm{d} t}\\ \end{aligned}\right. \] In order to make the description of the time integration algorithms less abstract, one can think of \(\mathbf{q},\mathbf{\dot q},\mathbf{\ddot q}\) as position, velocity and acceleration.</description></item><item><title>Fastest heterogeneous container and benchmarks</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/11/fastest-heterogeneous-container-and-benchmarks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/11/fastest-heterogeneous-container-and-benchmarks/</guid><description>While doing some benchmarks with the heterogeneous containers described here and here along with some related containers, I could not but notice the performance of entt, more specifically its registry class which relies on a modified sparse set data structure. In front of such witchcraft, I decided to delve behind the curtains and see for myself the performance of an heterogeneous container based on it.
Sparse sets Sparse sets are data structures widely covered (1, 2, 3, 4).</description></item><item><title>WTF C&amp;plus;&amp;plus;</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/wtf-cplusplus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/wtf-cplusplus/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this page, I enumerate various C++ fragments that sparkled my incomprehension when I encountered them, or made me scratch my head far too long. It is meant to be a reminder mainly for myself and destined to be updated over time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A simple heterogeneous container in C&amp;plus;&amp;plus; without relying on 'variant' nor 'any'</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/08/a-simple-heterogeneous-container-in-cplusplus-without-relying-on-variant-nor-any/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/08/a-simple-heterogeneous-container-in-cplusplus-without-relying-on-variant-nor-any/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a precedent post, I outlined the implementation of an heterogeneous dynamic array. Let us try now to reflect on what was done to draw some genericity out of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing an heterogeneous dynamic array in C&amp;plus;&amp;plus;</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/07/implementing-an-heterogeneous-dynamic-array-in-cplusplus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/07/implementing-an-heterogeneous-dynamic-array-in-cplusplus/</guid><description>Introduction heterogeneous: consisting of dissimilar or diverse constituents
dynamic array: a dynamic array is a random access, variable-size list data structure that allows elements to be added or removed. [&amp;hellip;] A simple dynamic array can be constructed by allocating an array of fixed-size, typically larger than the number of elements immediately required. The elements of the dynamic array are stored contiguously at the start of the underlying array, [&amp;hellip;]
Heterogeneous containers are data structures wherein elements can be of different types.</description></item><item><title>New paper published in Medical Engineering and Physics</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2020/07/new-paper-published-in-medical-engineering-and-physics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2020/07/new-paper-published-in-medical-engineering-and-physics/</guid><description>My paper titled Surface-based Modeling of Muscles: Functional Simulation of the Shoulder is now online ! Published in Medical Engineering and Physics journal at https://doi.org/10.1016/j.medengphy.2020.04.010</description></item><item><title>Welcome to my website, I will be your guide</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2020/03/welcome-to-my-website-i-will-be-your-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 19:21:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2020/03/welcome-to-my-website-i-will-be-your-guide/</guid><description>A warm welcome to my personal website. After a long maturation time, it is finally online! :tada:
It was developed from scratch with Hugo, a great static site generator, and inspired myself or sometimes reused bits from the nice Academic theme by Georges Cushen. During the journey, I learned a lot about html, css and hugo.
Why from scratch? For two main reasons: one is that I had a precise design in mind, and the other was that I wanted to keep it as minimal as possible for my needs.</description></item></channel></rss>