<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>research on My Personal Website</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/tags/research/</link><description>Recent content in research on My Personal Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fabien.pean.pro/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New paper published in Clinical Biomechanics</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2021/12/new-paper-published-in-clinical-biomechanics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2021/12/new-paper-published-in-clinical-biomechanics/</guid><description>My paper titled Computational analysis of subscapularis tears and pectoralis major transfers on muscular activity, published in Clinical Biomechanics, is now online ! It is freely accessible under a Creative Commons license, thanks to the agreement between ETH Zurich and Elsevier, at this url. This article brings a conclusion to a long journey as it is the last work elaborated during my PhD. Many thanks to my co-authors Dr. Philippe Favre and Prof.</description></item><item><title>New paper published in Journal of Biomechanics</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2021/11/new-paper-published-in-journal-of-biomechanics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2021/11/new-paper-published-in-journal-of-biomechanics/</guid><description>My paper titled Influence of rotator cuff integrity on loading and kinematics before and after reverse shoulder arthroplasty published in Journal of Biomechanics is now online ! It is freely accessible under a Creative Commons license, thanks to the agreement between ETH Zurich and Elsevier, at this url</description></item><item><title>Musculoskeletal Shoulder Simulation</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/projects/phd_shoulder/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/projects/phd_shoulder/</guid><description>Correct diagnosis and deep understanding of a condition is the general prerequisite for providing an optimal treatment. Injuries and diseases affecting the musculoskeletal system and their impact are difficult to reproduce in controlled and repeatable settings. Impairments greatly restrict the patient&amp;rsquo;s ability to carry out common daily tasks vital for remaining independent. In particular, many activities rely on the extensive reachability offered by the upper limb.
The shoulder offers the greatest range-of-motion in the whole human body and plays a key role in enabling the execution of common daily tasks vital for remaining independent, which is only possible thanks to its unique structure.</description></item><item><title>New paper published in Medical Engineering and Physics</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2020/07/new-paper-published-in-medical-engineering-and-physics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/news/2020/07/new-paper-published-in-medical-engineering-and-physics/</guid><description>My paper titled Surface-based Modeling of Muscles: Functional Simulation of the Shoulder is now online ! Published in Medical Engineering and Physics journal at https://doi.org/10.1016/j.medengphy.2020.04.010</description></item></channel></rss>