<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Constraint on My Personal Website</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/tags/constraint/</link><description>Recent content in Constraint on My Personal Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 19:23:31 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fabien.pean.pro/tags/constraint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nitsche method for weakly enforced Dirichlet boundary conditions</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/boundarycondition_weak_nitsche/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/notes/boundarycondition_weak_nitsche/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="disclaimer">Disclaimer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For the sake of simplicity, the following post focuses on weak
Dirichlet boundary conditions applied to the linear elastostatics
problem. This document reflects my understanding and interpretation of
the method. If you spot a mistake, please let me know !&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="context">Context&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Numerical models of physical systems are often represented as
Boundary Value Problem, which consists of a Partial Differential
Equation governing the domain accompanied by boundary conditions, known
values on the boundary of the domain. Boundary conditions are
effectively constraints: they are values that must be enforced at some
coordinates. Boundary conditions applied directly on the unknown field
are called essential or Dirichlet boundary conditions. The spatial
discretization required by the weak form of the problem is often chosen
to match the boundary of the domain of interest. Together with an
interpolating polynomial space, this enables to statically condense out
known values from the resulting linear system of equations. However,
this does not have to be the case, and the discretized space can cover
the domain of interest. In such cases, the essential boundary conditions
cannot be straightforwardly enforced.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>