<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on My Personal Website</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on My Personal Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 18:38:41 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deep down the FOSS: an unexpected journey</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2023/04/deep-down-the-foss-an-unexpected-journey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 18:38:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2023/04/deep-down-the-foss-an-unexpected-journey/</guid><description>&lt;!-- &lt;img src="an-unexpected-journey.jpg"/> -->
&lt;h2 id="once-upon-a-vegafem">Once upon a VegaFEM&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It all began with a spark&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On my spare time, I decided to sharpen my skills and change my mind by toying with &lt;a href="https://viterbi-web.usc.edu/~jbarbic/vega/">VegaFEM&lt;/a>, an open-source (&lt;a href="https://spdx.org/licenses/BSD-3-Clause.html">BSD-3-Clause&lt;/a>) middleware providing facilities for soft-body simulation in the realm of computer graphics. It has been developed by &lt;a href="http://www.jernejbarbic.com/">Jernej BarbiÄ&lt;/a> and his group over many years, yet, it does not have an official release on any major git repository hosting websites. Its distribution occurs through the personal webpage, and copies elsewhere are often ephemeral results of isolated contributors. I decided to give a go on my own with the latest version (4.0.0) and let &lt;a href="https://github.com/FabienPean/VegaFEM">my repository&lt;/a> join the rank of numerous forks. Doing so with this library offers the possibility to work on many aspects related to devops, maintenance, and development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fastest heterogeneous container and benchmarks</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/11/fastest-heterogeneous-container-and-benchmarks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/11/fastest-heterogeneous-container-and-benchmarks/</guid><description>&lt;p>While doing some benchmarks with the heterogeneous containers described &lt;a href="https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/07/implementing-an-heterogeneous-dynamic-array-in-cplusplus/">here&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/08/a-simple-heterogeneous-container-in-cplusplus-without-relying-on-variant-nor-any/">here&lt;/a> along with some related containers, I could not but notice the performance of &lt;a href="https://github.com/skypjack/entt">entt&lt;/a>, more specifically its &lt;em>registry&lt;/em> class which relies on a modified sparse set data structure. In front of such witchcraft, I decided to delve behind the curtains and see for myself the performance of an heterogeneous container based on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sparse-sets">Sparse sets&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Sparse sets are data structures widely covered (&lt;a href="https://programmingpraxis.com/2012/03/09/sparse-sets/">1&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/sparse-set/">2&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://skypjack.github.io/2019-09-25-ecs-baf-part-5/">3&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/176454.176484">4&lt;/a>). I will give a shot here and explain succinctly and as clear as possible the concepts behind the data structure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A simple heterogeneous container in C&amp;plus;&amp;plus; without relying on 'variant' nor 'any'</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/08/a-simple-heterogeneous-container-in-cplusplus-without-relying-on-variant-nor-any/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/08/a-simple-heterogeneous-container-in-cplusplus-without-relying-on-variant-nor-any/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="building-an-heterogeneous-container-basic-ingredients">Building an heterogeneous container: basic ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In a precedent post, I outlined the implementation of an heterogeneous dynamic array. Let us try now to reflect on what was done to draw some genericity out of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The basic ingredients to build an heterogeneous container are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>data&lt;/code> the object&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>ptr&lt;/code> where the object is stored: a pointer or offset allowing to find the object in memory&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>tag&lt;/code> what is the type of that object: a unique way to identify types at runtime.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>dtor&lt;/code> how to destroy the object: to avoid memory leaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(how to copy the object)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Numerous implementations can be obtained by combining these components together in various ways. For example, &lt;code>std::any&lt;/code> is basically a structure containing &lt;code>tag&lt;/code>, &lt;code>ptr&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>dtor&lt;/code> together. As such &lt;code>std::any&lt;/code> is self-contained and can be put into a vector without worries. While it is ideal for passing a single item around, having a collection of them is not so great.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing an heterogeneous dynamic array in C&amp;plus;&amp;plus;</title><link>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/07/implementing-an-heterogeneous-dynamic-array-in-cplusplus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabien.pean.pro/blog/2020/07/implementing-an-heterogeneous-dynamic-array-in-cplusplus/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/heterogeneous">&lt;code>heterogeneous&lt;/code>&lt;/a>: consisting of dissimilar or diverse constituents&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic_array">&lt;code>dynamic array&lt;/code>&lt;/a>: a dynamic array is a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Random_access">random access&lt;/a>, variable-size list &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_structure">data structure&lt;/a> that allows elements to be added or removed. [&amp;hellip;] A simple dynamic array can be constructed by allocating an array of fixed-size, typically larger than the number of elements immediately required. The elements of the dynamic array are stored contiguously at the start of the underlying array, [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Heterogeneous containers are data structures wherein elements can be of different types. &lt;code>struct&lt;/code> and &lt;code>std::tuple&lt;/code> are example of heterogeneous containers in C++. In contrast, arrays provided by the language or the standard library are homogeneous containers, their elements can only be of the same type. &lt;code>std::array&lt;/code> and &lt;code>std::vector&lt;/code> are examples of static array and dynamic array implementations, respectively.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>